Hi, Anna. The wind is getting colder, isn't it?
‫مرحبًا يا "آنا". تزداد الرياح برودة.‬
Huh? She's rather unfriendly today.
‫إنها غير ودودة اليوم.‬
Oh?
‫عجبًا.‬
Just coming home, Anna?
‫هل ستعودين إلى بيتك يا "آنا"؟‬
Nina!
‫"نينا"!‬
All the restaurants around here are already closed.
‫كل المطاعم قد أُغلقت هنا.‬
Let's go back to the hotel, Nina.
‫لنعد إلى الفندق يا "نينا".‬
What's wrong, Nina?
‫ما الخطب يا "نينا"؟‬
Everyone on this street… For some reason, they act as if they know me.
‫جميع من في الشارع يتعاملون معي‬ ‫كما لو أنهم يعرفونني.‬
They all call me Anna.
‫ينادونني جميعهم باسم "آنا".‬
Oh…
‫عجبًا…‬
This looks strange.
‫يبدو هذا غريبًا.‬
Even though Suk, a serial murder suspect, is being treated here,
‫مع أن "سوك" الذي اتُهّم بكونه سفّاحًا،‬ ‫يُعالج هنا،‬
there's not a single cop or patrol car here.
‫فما شرطي واحد هنا حتى ولا سيارة دورية.‬
You're right.
‫أنت محق.‬
At any rate, I'll check things out.
‫سأتفقد المكان على أي حال.‬
Well, regardless of what's up, I'll need to go with you.
‫بصرف النظر عمّا يحدث، فإنني سأرافقك.‬
It's the same inside.
‫الوضع نفسه في الداخل.‬
Not even a hint of the police.
‫ليس للشرطة أي وجود هنا.‬
Excuse me.
‫أرجو المعذرة.‬
I think you're caring for an injured man by the name of Suk.
‫أظن أن ثمة رجل مصاب‬ ‫يتلقى الرعاية هنا اسمك "سوك.‬
Jan Suk. He's a police officer.
‫"يان سوك". إنه شرطي.‬
A police officer?
‫شرطي؟‬
He was one of the injured men at the building on Bruno Street.
‫كان أحد المصابين الذين أُصيبوا‬ ‫في مبنى شارع "برونو".‬
Oh, one of those homeless men who got into a big fight.
‫أحد أولئك المشردين‬ ‫الذين انخرطوا في عراك كبير.‬
Homeless men? In a fight?
‫مشرّدون؟ عراك؟‬
Yes.
‫نعم.‬
I wondered what they were saying on the news.
‫ما الذي قد أٌذيع في الأخبار يا ترى؟‬
This must be what the story is.
‫لا بد أن هذا هو الخبر الذي أُذيع.‬
So, what room are those men in now?
‫إذًا، في أي غرفة يوجد هؤلاء الرجال الآن؟‬
They were pretty badly injured,
‫كانوا مصابين بجروح شديدة،‬
but they were transferred after being treated.
‫لكنهم نُقلوا بعد تلقي العلاج.‬
Transferred?
‫نُقلوا؟‬
Where to?
‫إلى أين؟‬
I'm not sure. All six of them were loaded into ambulances.
‫لست متأكدة. وُضعوا الستة في سيارات الإسعاف.‬
Six? That's the number of men who attacked us.
‫ستة؟ أهذا عدد من هاجمونا؟‬
What about Suk? Jan Suk, the police officer.
‫ماذا عن "سوك"؟ "يان سوك"، الشرطي.‬
He'd been shot.
‫كان قد أُطلق عليه النار.‬
None of the men brought to us had been shot.
‫ما من أحد من الرجال الذي نُقلوا إلينا‬ ‫قد أُطلق عليه النار.‬
Then is there any record of a man named Jan Suk being brought here?
‫ألا يرد في السجلات إذًا‬ ‫أن ثمة رجلًا قد نقل إلى هنا باسم "سوك"؟‬
No, there isn't.
‫لا.‬
Documents and a tape related to Kinderheim 511…
‫مستندات وشريط عن ميتم "كيندرهايم 511"…‬
Yeah. Petrov was the former director of Kinderheim 511
‫أجل. كان "بتروف"‬ ‫مدير ميتم "كيندرهايم 511" السابق‬
and was operating an unlicensed orphanage in Prague.
‫وكان يدير دار أيتام غير مرخصة في "براغ".‬
He gave them to me just before he died.
‫أعطاني إياها قبل موته مباشرةً.‬
And who wants them now?
‫من يريدها الآن؟‬
I'm not sure who wants them,
‫لست متأكدًا ممّن يريدها،‬
but those former Czechoslovakia secret police people are
‫لكم أفراد شرطة "تشيكوسلوفاكيا"‬ ‫السرية السابقة‬
trying to get their hands on them.
‫يحاولون الاستحواذ عليها.‬
Where are the documents and tape now?
‫أين المستندات والشريط الآن؟‬
They're not with me. Someone else is holding onto them.
‫ليست معي. ثمة شخص آخر يحتفظ بها.‬
It was for those
‫بسبب هؤلاء‬
that Suk was seriously injured and then abducted from the hospital.
‫تعرّض "سوك" إلى إصابات بالغة‬ ‫واختُطف من المستشفى.‬
Who knows what those people will do to Suk to get what they want.
‫من يدري ما قد يفعله هؤلاء‬ ‫لـ"سوك" للحصول على ما يريدونه.‬
What a mess.
‫يا لها من فوضى.‬
What's in those documents and on that tape?
‫ما الموجود في المستندات والشريط؟‬
The documents are research reports filled with technical terminology
‫المستندان عبارة‬ ‫عن تقارير بحثية مليئة بالمصطلحات،‬
and a list of names.
‫وفيها قائمة بأسماء.‬
I didn't look at them closely and only listened to part of the tape.
‫لم أتفقدها بتمعن‬ ‫وقد سمعت جزءًا فقط من الشريط.‬
What's on the tape?
‫ما المُسجّل على الشريط؟‬
A recording of a child.
‫إنه تسجيل لطفل.‬
A child?
‫طفل؟‬
The child is being questioned. I think he was drugged.
‫طفل يُستجوّب. أظن أنه كان مخدّرًا.‬
When asked his name, he said it was Johan.
‫عندما سُئل عن اسمه، أجاب "يوهان".‬
What's the matter, Dr. Tenma?
‫ما الخطب يا د. "تينما"؟‬
Kinderheim 511…
‫ميتم "كيندرهايم 511"…‬
Research reports…
‫تقارير بحثية…‬
Johan!
‫"يوهان"!‬
Where's the tape now?
‫أين الشريط الآن؟‬
Will you please come with me?
‫هلّا تأتيان معي.‬
Where's Suk?
‫أين "سوك"؟‬
Let's keep this businesslike.
‫لنتصرف بمهنية.‬
Will you please come with me?
‫هلّا تأتيان معي.‬
I'm okay with going along,
‫لا أمانع مجاراتهم،‬
but there's no reason for you to get involved in this as well, Dr. Tenma.
‫لكن ما من داع يستدعي انخراطك‬ ‫في هذه الأزمة أيضًا يا د. "تينما".‬
I don't mind.
‫لا أمانع ذلك.‬
I've got some questions of my own for the former Czechoslovakia secret police.
‫لديّ تساؤلات متعلقة بشرطة‬ ‫"تشيكوسلوفاكيا" السرية السابقة.‬
What the heck is it you're trying to do?
‫ما الذي تحاول فعله؟‬
Anyway,
‫لا يهم،‬
the real question is whether or not we'll be able to reason with these people.
‫السؤال الحقيقي هو ما إذا كنا سنتمكن‬ ‫من التفاهم مع هؤلاء الناس أم لا.‬
Don't tell me you brought us here to treat us to dinner, did you?
‫لا تقل إنك أحضرتنا إلى هنا‬ ‫لتدعونا على العشاء، أليس كذلك؟‬
Welcome.
‫مرحبًا بكما.‬
Please, have a seat over here.
‫تفضّلا بالجلوس هنا.‬
I know that man.
‫أعرف ذلك الرجل.‬
He was probably a big shot in the former Czechoslovakia secret police.
‫كان على الأرجح شخصية بارزة‬ ‫في شرطة "تشيكوسلوفاكيا" السرية السابقة.‬
Yeah, I saw him in an old newspaper article.
‫أجل، رأيته في مقالة صحفية قديمة.‬
He's Captain Karel Ranke.
‫إنه النقيب "كاريل رانك".‬
So, we finally meet the top brass.
‫قابلنا كبيرهم أخيرًا.‬
I am terribly sorry for the rough treatment by my subordinates.
‫أعتذر بشدة عن تعامل مرؤوسيّ العنيف.‬
It was a slip-up in the chain of command that led to this unintended situation.
‫طرأت زلة في التسلسل القيادي‬ ‫وقد أدت إلى هذا الموقف غير المقصود.‬
We have become deeply misunderstood not only by you but by all of society.
‫لقد أُسيء فهمنا تمامًا منكما‬ ‫وبل ومن المجتمع بأكمله.‬
We're seen as a gang of murderers now.
‫يُنظر إلينا الآن على أننا عصابة من القتلة.‬
Where's Suk?
‫أين "سوك"؟‬
He's being taken care of at one of our hospitals.
‫يُعتنى به في إحدى مستشفياتنا.‬
His life is not in danger.
‫حياته ليست في خطر.‬
This isn't just some misunderstanding.
‫هذا ليس مجرد سوء تفاهم.‬
Our people did not kill a single person in all these incidents.
‫لم تقتل جماعتنا أي شخص في كلّ تلك الحوادث.‬
What about that woman?
‫ماذا عن المرأة؟‬
What woman?
‫أي امرأة؟‬
Isn't that blonde woman taking orders from you?
‫ألم تكن المرأة الشقراء تنفّذ أوامرك؟‬
I've heard about her,
‫سمعت عنها،‬
but she's not part of our organization at all.
‫لا علاقة لها بمنظمتنا نهائيًا.‬
In fact, she's causing us lots of trouble.
‫بل إنها تتسبب لنا في الكثير من المتاعب.‬
We're not trying to kill anyone.
‫لم نكن نحاول قتل أحد.‬
A German associate of ours wants those documents and tape.
‫ثمة شريك ألماني لنا‬ ‫يريد المستندات والشريط.‬
We were in serious negotiations with Petrov.
‫كنا نجري مفاوضات جادة مع "بتروف".‬
But he was killed just as we began.
‫لكنه قُتل ما إن بدأنا المفاوضات.‬
There must be a lot of money involved.
‫لا بد أن ثمة مكاسب مالية كبيرة.‬
That's right. This is all about business.
‫صحيح. إنه عمل.‬
I simply want to talk business here.
‫أريد ببساطة مناقشة تفاصيل العمل.‬
I'll exchange Suk for that tape and those records.
‫سأقايض "سوك" بذلك الشريط وتلك التسجيلات.‬
I don't know where they are.
‫لا أعرف مكانها.‬
Let's not have that kind of negotiating.
‫لا داعي لخوض هذا النوع من التفاوضات.‬
That kind of thing should never happen again.
‫يجب ألا تتكرر تجربة كهذه.‬
Who knows what would happen if that kind of thing got out again.
‫من يدري ما قد يحدث‬ ‫أن انتشرت تجربة كهذه مجددًا.‬
That kind of thing should never happen again.
‫يجب ألّا تتكرر مجددًا.‬
Now is not the time for discussion of those things.
‫لسنا في وقت مناسب لمناقشة هذه المسألة.‬
It has nothing to do with this negotiation.
‫إذ ليست لها علاقة بتفاوضنا هذا.‬
I am from that place.
‫كنت جزءًا من ذلك المكان.‬
I come from Kinderheim 511.
‫أنا من ميتم "كيندرهايم 511".‬
How old are you?
‫كم عمرك؟‬
When did you get out?
‫متى خرجت؟‬
I was told that I was 14 then.
‫قيل لي إنني كنت في الـ14 حينها.‬
That was 30 years ago.
‫أي قبل 30 عامًا.‬
When did you go in?
‫متى دخلته؟‬
I don't know. Probably when I was seven or eight.
‫لا أعرف. لعلّي دخلته‬ ‫عندما كنت في السابعة أو الثامنة.‬
Then around 1963, right?
‫في قرابة عام 1963 إذًا، صحيح؟‬
Maybe.
‫ربما.‬
Do you know this boy?
‫هل تعرف هذا الفتى؟‬
He's my nephew.
‫إنه ابن أختي.‬
In the early 60's,
‫في بداية الستينيات،‬
I was ostensibly stationed at the Czechoslovakian embassy in Berlin
‫كنت قد عُيّنت في الظاهر‬ ‫في سفارة "تشيكوسلوفاكيا" في "برلين"،‬
but worked as an intelligence officer.
‫لكنني كنت ضابطًا في المخابرات.‬
I had a younger sister who married a German.
‫كانت لديّ أخت صغيرة تزوجت من ألماني.‬
She and her husband tried to defect over the Berlin Wall
‫حاولت هي وزوجها الهرب عبر جدار "برلين"‬
but were shot and killed during their attempt.
‫لكنهما قُتلا أثناء محاولتهما الهرب.‬
Their son, that boy, remained behind.
‫ابنهما، ذلك الفتى، بقي هناك.‬
I signed the papers that put him there.
‫وقّعت على الأوراق التي أُدخل بها في الميتم.‬
From what I was told, it sounded like a magnificent place.
‫وجدته مكانًا رائعًا ممّا قيل لي.‬
It was the ideal educational facility
‫كانت المؤسسة التعليمية المثالية‬
that would raise children with a checkered past to become
‫التي قد تربّي أطفالًا بماض مضطرب‬
the elite backbone of the future communist party.
‫ركيزة الحزب الشيوعي المستقبلي من النخبة.‬
I signed the papers that put him into Kinderheim 511.
‫وقّعت على الأوراق التي أُدخل بها‬ ‫في ميتم "كيندرهايم 511".‬
I don't know.
‫لا أعرف.‬
I have no memories of my time there or from before then.
‫ليس لديّ ذكريات عن الوقت الذي قضيته هناك‬ ‫أو عمّا سبقه من وقت.‬
I don't remember any of it.
‫لا أتذّكر شيئًا عنها.‬
I don't even know my real name.
‫لا أعرف حتى اسمي الحقيقي.‬
You…
‫أنت…‬
You're trying to make money off of something so reprehensible.
‫تحاول جني المال من تصرف مستنكر كهذا.‬
You're trying to sell
‫تحاول بيع‬
the research data obtained from experiments on your own nephew.
‫البيانات البحثية الناتجة عن تجارب‬ ‫أُجريت على ابن أختك.‬
We've gone off-topic.
‫خرجنا عن موضوع التفاوض.‬
I'd like us to continue this negotiation in a businesslike way.
‫أريد أن نكمل هذه المفاوضات بطريقة مهنية.‬
All right.
‫حسنًا.‬
We'll end things here for today.
‫سننهي نقاشنا لهذا اليوم.‬
I hope we can reach an agreement.
‫أرجو أن نصل إلى اتفاق.‬
Take them where they'd like to go.
‫خذاهما إلى حيث يودان الذهاب.‬
What should we do?
‫ماذا ينبغي أن نفعل؟‬
What's most important right now is saving Suk.
‫أهم ما يجب فعله الآن هو إنقاذ "سوك".‬
I think he'll release Suk if we give him what he wants.
‫أظن أنه سيطلق سراح‬ ‫"سوك" إن أعطيناه ما يريده.‬
Mr. Grimmer?
‫سيد "غريمر"؟‬
Cocoa…
‫الكاكاو…‬
I remember.
‫تذكّرت.‬
I remember!
‫تذكّرت!‬
Mr. Grimmer!
‫سيد "غريمر"!‬
Our weekly serving of cocoa…
‫حصتنا الأسبوعية من الكاكاو…‬
He loved that serving of cocoa!
‫أحب ما يُقدّم له من كاكاو.‬
When I had a fever and was laid up in the infirmary,
‫عندما أُصبت بالحمى ووضعت في المستوصف،‬
he brought me his cocoa.
‫أعطاني حصته من الكاكاو.‬
He brought me his own cocoa even though he loved it so much!
‫أحضر لي حصته من الكاكاو مع أنه أحبه كثيرًا.‬
It was delicious.
‫كان لذيذًا.‬
I'd never had cocoa as delicious as that before.
‫لم يسبق لي أن تناولت كاكاو بهذه اللذة.‬
So I wanted to do something to return the favor.
‫لذلك أردت أن أرد له جميله.‬
That's when he told me,
‫قال لي حينئذ،‬
"Just remember me."
‫"تذكرني فحسب."‬
It was a popular thing for us to do then.
‫كان تصرفًا شائعًا نُقدم عليه.‬
We would tell our friends about ourselves.
‫كنا نخبر أصدقاءنا عن أنفسنا.‬
I don't know why, but during the creepy lessons,
‫لا أعرف السبب،‬ ‫لكن في أثناء تلقي الدروس المرعبة،‬
the memories of ourselves slowly faded away day after day.
‫تلاشت ذكرياتنا ببطء يومًا بعد يوم.‬
We realized we'd even forget our own names.
‫أدركنا أن أسماءنا حتى سننساها.‬
That's why… we had our friends remember who we were for us.
‫لهذا السبب طلبنا من أصدقائنا أن يتذكرونا.‬
He loved cocoa! He loved drawing pictures!
‫كان يحب الكاكاو ويحب الرسم.‬
He loved insects!
‫كان يحب الحشرات.‬
But he hated preserving insects because it would kill them.
‫لكنه كره حفظ الحشرات لأنها ممارسة تقتلها.‬
The most fun he had was when he went to the forest with his parents.
‫أكثر ما استمتع به‬ ‫كان الذهاب مع والديه إلى الغابة.‬
They caught lots of butterflies.
‫اصطادوا فراشات كثيرة.‬
But he released them from the insect cage just before they left.
‫لكنه أطلق سراحها قبل أن يغادروا.‬
His dream was to become an entomologist!
‫كان حلمه أن يصبح عالم حشرات!‬
His…
‫كان…‬
His name was…
‫اسمه كان…‬
Adolf Reinhart.
‫"أدولف راينهارت".‬
That was my nephew.
‫كان هو ابن أختي.‬
Welcome back.
‫عودًا حميدًا.‬
Keeping secrets from him is a no-no.
‫يُمنع إخفاء الأسرار عنه.‬
People can become…
‫بوسع الناس…‬
whatever they want to be.
‫أن يصبحوا أيًا ما يريدونه.‬
Cheers!
‫في صحتكم!‬
Hey, welcome back.
‫عودًا حميدًا.‬
What's wrong, Nina?
‫ما الخطب يا "نينا"؟‬
I…
‫أنا…‬
I know this place.
‫أعرف هذا المكان.‬
I know the street here…
‫أعرف هذا الشارع…‬
And the scenery…
‫وهذا المنظر…‬
And this sign.
‫أعرف هذه اللافتة.‬
I know all of these things.
‫أعرف كل شيء.‬
Did you live here?
‫هل عشت هنا؟‬
I don't know, but…
‫لا أعرف ولكن…‬
But what?
‫لكن ماذا؟‬
I'm afraid.
‫أشعر بالخوف.‬
You know this door too?
‫أتعرفين هذا الباب أيضًا؟‬
I don't know, but…
‫لا أعرف ولكن…‬
I'm afraid…
‫أنا خائفة…‬
These stairs too…
‫هذا الدرج…‬
I know them.
‫أعرفه.‬
Mr. Grimmer, after thinking about it all night,
‫سيد "غريمر"،‬ ‫بعدما بقيت أفكر في الأمر طوال الليل،‬
there's something I want to tell you.
‫وجدت أن ثمة ما أريد إخبارك به.‬
Dr. Tenma, that tape and those documents really aren't any of your concern.
‫د. "تينما"، ذلك الشريط وتلك المستندات‬ ‫لا شأن لك بها.‬
But yes, they are.
‫بلى، إنها تعنيني.‬
Looks like we won't have time to talk.
‫يبدو أننا لن نحظى بوقت للتحدث.‬
It appears they want to get on with the negotiations.
‫يبدو أنهم يريدون إتمام المفاوضات.‬
The former Czechoslovakia secret police have come all the way here to see us.
‫أتت شرطة "تشيكوسلوفاكيا" السرية السابقة‬ ‫من بعيد لمقابلتنا.‬
Have you thought it over carefully?
‫هل فكّرت مليًا فيما عُرض؟‬
Yeah. I'm not giving you the tape or the research papers.
‫نعم. لن أعطيك الشريط والأوراق البحثية.‬
So you don't care what happens to Detective Suk?
‫لا تأبه إذًا بما سيحدث للمحقق "سوك"؟‬
If anything happens to Suk,
‫إن أصاب "سوك" أي مكروه،‬
the tape and documents will disappear forever.
‫ستختفي المستندات والشريط إلى الأبد.‬
Threats like that will get you nowhere.
‫لن تفيدك مثل تلك التهديدات.‬
However,
‫لكنني‬
I am willing to let you listen to the tape.
‫مستعد للسماح لك بسماع الشريط.‬
In exchange,
‫في المقابل،‬
you'll forget about trying to sell it to that German associate of yours.
‫ستدعك من فكرة بيعه لشريكك الألماني.‬
If you'd like to listen to the tape in private, then I'll gladly let you.
‫إن أردت الاستماع للشريط على انفراد،‬ ‫فسيسرني السماح لك بذلك.‬
In fact, I think you should listen to it.
‫بل يجب أن تسمعه.‬
For the sake of your nephew who you sent to Kinderheim 511,
‫من أجل ابن أختك الذي أرسلته‬ ‫إلى ميتم "كيندرهايم 511".‬
you should listen to the voice of the boy named Johan that's on that tape.
‫يجب أن تسمع صوت الصبي‬ ‫الذي يُدعى "يوهان" والمُسجّل على الشريط.‬
That's the deal you're offering me?
‫أهذا هو عرضك؟‬
I'm not trying to make a deal.
‫لا أحاول أن أعقد صفقة.‬
Stop this!
‫كفاك!‬
There's no time for this.
‫ما من وقت لهذا.‬
While we're sitting here doing this, someone could get killed over that tape.
‫بينما نجلس نحن هنا،‬ ‫ثمة من يُقتل بسبب ذلك الشريط.‬
Don't you realize how many of your Czechoslovakia secret police
‫ألا تدرك كم رجلًا من شرطتك السرية‬
have been killed in these incidents?
‫قد قُتل في تلك الحوادث؟‬
Who do you think killed them?
‫من قتلهم برأيك؟‬
It's the person who wants that tape most of all.
‫إن أكثر من يرغب في الحصول على الشريط.‬
whose voice is on that tape.
‫إنه الشخص المُسجّل صوته على الشريط.‬
It's Johan!
‫إنه "يوهان"!‬
Dr. Tenma?
‫د. "تينما"؟‬
I have no idea what you're talking about.
‫لا أعرف عمّا تتحدث.‬
Don't play dumb!
‫لا تتظاهر بالجهل!‬
I know your German associate told you what's on that tape!
‫أعرف أن شريكك الألماني‬ ‫أخبرك بما يوجد في الشريط.‬
What is it he told you you'd find?
‫بم أخبرك بشأن ما ستجده؟‬
"The monster's identity." That's all.
‫"هوية الوحش". هذا ما كلّ ما قاله.‬
I didn't want to get you people mixed up in this.
‫لا أريدكم أن تُقحموا في هذه المسألة.‬
But before anyone else gets killed, I need to tell you about what happened…
‫لكن قبل أن يُقتل أحد آخر،‬ ‫يجب أن أخبرك بما حدث…‬
ten years ago.
‫قبل عشر سنوات.‬
I see.
‫فهمت.‬
So, this Johan came here to Prague in search of his roots?
‫إذًا المدعو "يوهان" قد أتي إلى "براغ"‬ ‫بحثًا عن أصوله؟‬
I'm not sure.
‫لست متأكدًا.‬
He may have come here to erase them.
‫لعلّه أتى لمحوها.‬
What did you people do 15 years ago?
‫ماذا فعلتم قبل 15 عامًا؟‬
A mother and child lived near Cedok Bridge in Michalska.
‫كانت تعيش امرأة وابنها‬ ‫بالقرب من جسر "تشيدوك" في "ميكالسكا".‬
One day, they were abducted by the secret police.
‫اختطفتهما الشرطة السرية في يوم من أيام.‬
When you took Johan from the building with the three frogs,
‫عندما أخذتم "يوهان" من مبنى الثلاثة ضفادع،‬
what did you do to him?
‫ماذا فعلتم به؟‬
THREE FROGS
‫"(الثلاثة ضفادع)"‬
These stairs…
‫هذا الدرج…‬
My big brother…
‫أخي الكبير…‬
What's wrong, Nina?
‫ما الخطب يا "نينا"؟‬
He was dragged away down these stairs.
‫جُرّ إلى أسفل الدرج.‬
Who was?
‫من؟‬
My brother.
‫أخي.‬
Admittedly, in my position at the time, I knew everything that went on.
‫أقرّ بأن منصبي آنذاك‬ ‫سمح لي بمعرفة كل ما كان يجري.‬
But three frogs? Abduction of a mother and child?
‫لكن الثلاثة ضفادع؟ وخطف امرأة وابنها؟‬
I don't remember that at all.
‫لا أتذكّر أيًا من مطلقًا.‬
Don't play dumb!
‫لا تدّع الجهل!‬
In truth, there were some things that I never heard about.
‫في الحقيقة، ثمة أمور لم أسمع بها قط.‬
The things a certain man did.
‫أمور أقدم على فعلها شخص.‬
I never knew what department of the secret police
‫لم أعرف في أي أقسام الشرطة السرية‬
he was assigned to or who he took orders from.
‫قد عُيّن أو ممّن كان يتلقى الأوامر.‬
He freely detained many people,
‫أخذ في اعتقال الكثير من الناس بلا رقيب،‬
but for some reason, he never had to report it to anyone.
‫ولسبب ما لم يكن يبلغ أحدًا بها.‬
I have no idea what he was doing.
‫ليست لديّ فكرة عمّا فعله.‬
He was only a mere lieutenant,
‫كان ملازمًا ليس إلا،‬
but he was given a luxurious mansion to work out of.
‫لكنه مُنح قصرًا فاخرًا ليعمل منه.‬
Ah, yes. He was called the "Man of Red Rose Mansion."
‫أجل. كان يُلقّب بـ"رجُل قصر الوردة الحمراء".‬
Do you think he had anything to do with this?
‫أتظن أن لا علاقة بهذا الأمر؟‬
He was a very refined and quiet man.
‫كان رجلًا مهذّبًا جدًا وهادئًا.‬
He never wore a uniform and loved having tea and cake.
‫لم يرتد زيًا رسميًا قط‬ ‫وكان يحب تناول الشاي والكعك.‬
What's his name?
‫ما اسمه؟‬
Franz Bonaparta.
‫"فرانس بونابارتا".‬
However, I don't know if that is his real name.
‫لكنني لا أعرف‬ ‫ما إن كان هذا اسمه الحقيقي أم لا.‬
He also had a pen name.
‫بل وكان لديه اسم مستعار.‬
A pen name?
‫اسم مستعار؟‬
He also wrote picture books.
‫كان يؤلّف الكتب المصوّرة أيضًا.‬
Does this door scare you too?
‫هل يخيفك هذا الباب أيضًا؟‬
I…
‫أنا…‬
I… read a picture book inside here.
‫قرأت كتابًا مصوّرًا في الداخل.‬
Someone opened this door…
‫فتح أحدهم هذا الباب…‬
and came back.
‫وعاد.‬
Picture books?
‫كتابًا مصوّرًا؟‬
Yes. They were creepy picture books.
‫نعم. كانت كتبًا مصوّرة مخيفة.‬
One was called "The Nameless Monster."
‫أحدها بعنوان "وحش بلا اسم".‬
There's nothing here, Nina.
‫ما من شيء هنا يا "نينا".‬
What is this memory?
‫ما هذه الذكرى؟‬
I thought I was here reading a picture book,
‫حسبت أنني كنت أقرأ هنا كتابًا مصوّرًا،‬
but the person who opened the door and came back…
‫لكن الشخص الذي فتح الباب وعاد…‬
was me.
‫هو أنا.‬
Did I come back to me?
‫هل عدت إليّ أنا؟‬
Welcome back.
‫عودًا حميدًا.‬